Y'all, I'm telling you what, this is absolutely why I love social media. I love the TikTok
community. Because in a video, I was talking about the Security Council resolution being
vetoed and Great Britain abstaining and what that meant. I had this brilliant, well-informed
individual drop a question in my comment section, specifically asking, can the UN Secretary
General invoke Article 377 now? And when I say I fallute to Google to look this up,
I mean, quick. So what is this? Well, this is called the Uniting for Peace Resolution.
And it states that in any cases where the Security Council, because of the lack of unanimity,
I cannot say the word, a unanimous vote among its five permanent members. So when they're beefing,
if they fail to act as required to maintain international security and peace,
the General Assembly shall consider the matter immediately and may issue appropriate
recommendations to UN members for collective measures, including the use of armed force
when necessary in order to maintain and restore international security and peace. The resolution
was designed to provide the UN with an alternative avenue for action when at least one of the P5,
the permanent five members, uses its veto to obstruct the Security Council from carrying out its
functions mandated by the UN Charter. So how does this happen? Well, to facilitate prop action
by the General Assembly in the case of a deadlocked Security Council, the resolution created the
mechanism of the emergency special session. So what is the procedure for calling an emergency
special session? So I think it's Rule 8A, I can't see through her comment section, is at the request of
Security Council or members. So emergency special sessions can be convened by a vote of nine members
of the Security Council or a majority of United Nations member states. These sessions must be convened
within 24 hours of any vote. 9B allows a member state of the United Nations to request the Secretary
General to convene an emergency special session. Rule 10 and notification requires the Secretary
General to notify member states at least 12 hours in advance of the opening of an emergency special
session concern it, concern convened pursuant to Rule 8B. Agenda Rule 16 states the provisional
agenda of an emergency special session shall be communicated to member states simultaneously with the
communication convening to session. 19, during an emergency special session, additional agenda items
may be added for consideration by two-thirds majority if the members present in voting. And then Rule 20
just requires an item proposed for inclusion in the agenda to be accompanied by an explanatory
memorandum. So I will say it's not the Secretary General who invokes Article 377, but the existence of
resolution 377A. I have not heard of it before. But this definitely represents a very, very interesting
step that can now be taken. Another interesting thing to note about the resolution 377A is that
the United for Peace resolution was actually initiated by the United States, which they proposed and
initiated as a means of circumventing Soviet votes during the course of the Korean War.
It is worth pondering for a moment on the full circle moment here for the U.S.
Anyways, there you have it. Resolution 377A, the Uniting for Peace resolution. Will it be a next step?
Seems like the logical next step. I don't know. What do you guys think? Let me know in the comment
section. And share this with anybody you know who may have lost some hope in the United Nations
and their inability to be effective. Well, I can't say I didn't lose hope in the U.N. because I didn't
really have a lot of hope they'd be effective in this situation anyways. I can't say this has put
a smile on my face. So once again, big thanks to this user for referencing this, for dropping this
question. Like I said, I love this community. I love learning new shit every day. It's like I
learned something new, right? And so I appreciate you guys. Like and share, spread the information.
The more information and knowledge you have, the more difficult it is to be manipulated.